Sometimes we leave everything to find ourselves.
Two Lovers is a drama, romance film directed by James Gray.
A depressed man moves back in with his parents following a
recent heartbreak and finds himself with two women.
Leonard Kraditor, played by Joaquin Phoenix.
Michelle Rausch, played by Gwyneth Paltrow.
Sandra Cohen, played by Vinessa Shaw.
Ruth Kraditor, played by Isabella Rossellini.
Reuben Kraditor, played by Moni Moshonov.
Ronald Blatt, played by Elias Koteas.
Two Lovers is a 2008 American romantic drama film, directed by James Gray, and
starring Joaquin Phoenix, Gwyneth Paltrow, and Vinessa Shaw.
The film takes its inspiration from Fyodor Dostoyevsky's 1848 short story "White Nights", which had already
been turned into a film seven times, first by Luchino Visconti: Le Notti Bianche (1957).
It is set in the largely Russian Jewish neighborhood Brighton Beach in
New York City, as was Gray's first film Little Odessa.
Two Lovers premiered in competition at the 2008 Cannes Film Festival in May.
The film was Gray's third to enter the competition at this festival.
It was released on February 13, 2009.
The film explores themes of new year's eve, new york city, love
of one's life, neighbor, brooklyn, new york city.
The tone is emotional.